#### George R. Chichirau

237 Tremont St #3, Somerville MA 02143 | 617-319-4086 | george.chichirau@umb.edu | georgechichirau.com | public.tableau.com/app/profile/george.chichirau

#### **Summary**

Team-oriented professional with ample experience in quantitative research and project management. Strong research and publishing skills acquired through PhD-level coursework in public policy, statistics, and economics, and excellent communication skills developed through teaching and working in a start-up business environment.

#### **Selected Publications**

Tafoya B., DeBarcelos C., Chichirau G. & Hershman H. 2022. <u>Five-Year Statutory Fiscal Impact Report 2022</u>. Office of the Massachusetts State Auditor.

Tafoya B., DeBarcelos C., Chichirau G. & Hershman H. 2022. <u>Fulfilling the Promise of Local Aid by Strengthening State-Local Partnerships</u>. Office of the Massachusetts State Auditor.

Anderson, J., Moyer, J., Chichirau, G. 2022. <u>Public Policymaking (9th Edition)</u>. Cengage Learning.

Johnson, Michael P., Hollander, J., Kinsey, E., Chichirau, G. 2021. <u>Supporting Shrinkage:</u> <u>Better Planning and Decision-Making for Legacy Cities.</u> Albany, NY: SUNY University Press.

Midgley, G., Johnson, M. P., & Chichirau, G. (2018). What is Community Operational Research? European Journal of Operational Research, 268(3), 771–783.

Johnson, M. P., Midgley, G., & Chichirau, G. (2018). <u>Emerging Trends and New Frontiers in Community Operational Research</u>. European Journal of Operational Research, 268(3), 1178–1191.

Johnson, M. P., Midgley, G., Wright, J., & Chichirau, G. (2018). <u>Community Operational Research: Innovations, internationalization and agenda-setting applications.</u> European Journal of Operational Research, 268(3), 761–770.

#### Work Experience

### Office of the Massachusetts State Auditor Policy Research Analyst

**2021** – present

Designed, developed, and implemented statistical and econometric methods and techniques to undergird the agency's research agenda. Created data models (in Stata) and dashboards (in Tableau) to both measure and illustrate state policy impacts. Collaboratively authored wide-ranging research reports, including a five-year review of the entire activity of the Office of the State Auditor. Conducted reviews of numerous state programs, including education, school transportation, general government aid, and more. Served as advisor to the Director of the Division of Local Mandates.

### Northeastern University (Department of Political Science) Lecturer

2020 - present

Teaching history:

- POLS 2358: Current Issues in Cities and Suburbs (undergraduate). An in-depth introduction to pressing urban issues: urban sprawl, poverty, education, transportation, economic development, and housing, through an intensive analysis of the Boston area.
- POLS 2400 Quantitative Techniques (undergraduate). Methods of quantitative analysis including descriptive statistics, hypothesis testing, cross-tabulation, analysis of variance, bivariate regression and correlation, and multiple regression. Examines how to generate and interpret statistical findings through use of Excel, SPSS, and/or other software programs. Uses examples from political behavior, public policy analysis, public opinion, comparative and international politics, and other areas of political and social-science inquiry to emphasize practical applications.

# University of Massachusetts (McCormack Graduate School of Policy) Lecturer/Graduate Teaching Assistant 2017 – present

#### Teaching history:

- UPCD 620: Analytic Methods for Urban Planning (graduate). An introduction to quantitative and qualitative analytic methods appropriate to propose, support and evaluate localized and regional initiatives in planning and community development. Students use Stata to manage large datasets and produce descriptive summaries, plots, and inferential analyses (including regression).
- POLSCI 102: Government and Politics of the United States (undergraduate). A class on political principles and ideologies, public opinion, political socialization, political parties, mass media, elections, interest groups, civil rights and civil liberties, public policies and more.

- PPOL-G 621: Microeconomics for Policy Analysis (doctoral). A class focusing on consumer choices, producer behavior, and market failures, first within the neoclassical economic model and then in the context of alternative economic theories.
- GCPA 602: History of US Public Administration (graduate). A broad exposure to the intellectual history of public administration in the United States.
- PUBADM 628: Research Methods for Policy Analysis I (graduate). The course is divided into three sections, (1) quantitative methods; (2) qualitative methods; and (3) community-based participatory action research. Each section culminates in the submission of a policy brief on a topic of the student's choosing.
- PUBADM 629: Research Methods II (graduate). A focus on the Case Study Method and its related skills, including interviewing, analysis of documents/archives, analysis of prior research findings, qualitative research skills and analysis, and determination of policy implications.
- PUBADM 691: Capstone/Case Study Seminar. The completion of a final project, which may be a case study of a public policy or significant piece of legislation. While completing their case study project, students participate in a weekly seminar that focuses on case study methodology.

# INFORMS (The Institute for Operations Research and Management Sciences) Research Project Manager 2018 – 2020

- Managing the <u>INFORMS Editor's Cut edition on diversity issues</u>. I proposed relevant papers, integrated the collection with papers proposed by other committee members, and saw it through to final product.
- Developing a diversity knowledge base: establishing technical standards, performing a wide-ranging review, collecting and publishing materials, maintenance etc.

## University of Massachusetts (McCormack Graduate School of Policy) Graduate Research Assistant 2015 – 2021

- Dissertation research on public transit funding: I examined to what extent the MBTA could transition from a revenue stream dependent on budgetary allocations to one dependent on real estate. This included spatial and econometric modeling of the likely economic and social consequences of the MBTA functioning under different financing models.
- I contributed to 4 publications; I notably wrote chapter 2 of "Supporting Shrinkage: Better Planning and Decision-Making for Legacy Cities", a quantitative analysis of how data and technologies can support sustainable and equitable urban planning in legacy cities (and did most of the data analysis for the entire volume).
- I worked on the Public Administration Master's Program marketing in the following areas: 1) data analysis of enrollment and financial trends; 2) market analysis of comparable programs across the US; 3) lead development; and 4) social media development.

#### Wellington Solar LLC

### Project Manager

2014 - 2015

- I re-designed the company web site, implemented a major IT systems upgrade, and re-tooled the marketing portfolio.

#### **Education**

- University of Massachusetts (Boston) Ph.D. (ABD)
- University of Massachusetts (Boston) M.S. in Public Policy, 2017
- Carleton College B.A. (Magna Cum Laude) 2009

#### **Skills**

- Strong research skills acquired through PhD-level coursework in statistics, economics and political science.
- Proficient in Stata, MaxQDA, Tableau; working knowledge of ArcGIS, Excel, R, SQL.
- Languages: French, Romanian, Portuguese.